So, like what I told you in the previous clip, the first thing that we need to do is go ahead and take this seam out.
And most pants have a tack here.
Sometimes it is sewn.
Sometimes it is done with a needle like a little tack.
But, I like to use a razor blade to take things a part.
You can use a seamer ripper if you want.
You just make a little tiny cut.
Bring that down.
You do it to all sides.
And these are always done right at the seam .
There we go.
The seam in the middle right here.
They're never going to be over here.
They're always in the same spot.
Let's just go ahead and cut this one too.
Be real careful if you are using a razor blade.
You don't want to cut your pants.
These types of clothing, they'll fray pretty easily.We'll have that one open. Now that we have that done, we're going to be taking out this chain-stich.
That keeps the hem up.
And that's a blind stich and usually they're right here in the corner where the seams are.
You just have to look for a small piece of thread hanging out.
See there's a leap right there.
I'm pretty sure, that's right where the blind stich starts.
Yeah, that's it.
You just pop that out and it just pulls right out.
And this is the reason that a lot of men's pants the hems will come undone because if you pull one thread like that, and I'm sure this has happen to you before, the hem is out.
And now we have to go do the other one.
Let me open this up.
You just kind of look around.
And there it is.
You can kind of see it because it the seam overlaps itself.
I think that's it.
That might not be it.
Okay.
Maybe it takes you just a minute, but that's okay.
Oh, I think it's the wrong side.
Let me look on the other side.
Even me, it takes me several times.
I think there it is right there.
See usually the tell-tell is when the piece of thread is hanging out.
Pull that.
There we go.
Let me just yank this thing out.
Okay.
So, now that we have the hem undone, we're going to lay it out and in the next clip we're going to talk about the measurements and why we're going to mark it the way that we're going to mark it.
So, let's do that in the next clip.